Steven Miller is counselor to the
president and deputy um chief of staff.
He's also he's also one of the
the intellectual
sort of fathers of of MAGA
purportedly.
>> But he is second term than first term or
am I mistaken about that?
>> More second term than first term.
>> Yeah. Um he gave an interview yesterday
to Jake Tapper on CNN in which he said
some incredibly provocative things. Um
he called
treaty he called international treaties
where countries you know promise not to
invade each other international
nicities.
International nicities that can be
ignored.
>> These are solemn promises that literally
have been on the basis of international
affairs for
>> Yes. you know, thousands of years.
Really? Yes. I mean,
>> that's exactly right. So, he also said
uh in the context of the conversation
that you and I are having right now that
um the United States will will invade
Greenland, we will take Greenland. that
it he called it an integral part of the
United States which is preposterous
but it's an integral part of the United
States and it is a necessity for the
security and safety of the United
States. We already have a military base
there. We have for decades
and the danger
>> and those are international waters that
he's talking about anyway, right? like
even if we occupied Greenland,
>> the ships that he's supposed so worried
about would remain unimpeded in those in
those waters.
>> That's exactly right.
>> Russian and Chinese ships are not in
Danish/ Greenlander waters.
>> No. No, they're not. They never have
been. And um and so it's like he's
preparing us for an American invasion of
a NATO country. A NATO country.
>> [snorts]
>> This is unprecedented. It's it's
territory that's never been that's never
been sort of forwarded before. So what
do we do? Does that mean that NATO is
going to have to attack the United
States in order to save Greenland for
the Danes? I mean, that's really that's
what the treaty says.
>> And as I was joking to with you before,
under article 5,
>> the United States would be obligated to
come to Greenland's defense against the
United States.
>> Yeah. We would have to attack ourselves
according to the treaty.
>> Now the advantage is we have a good shot
at this. I think this is a war we can
win.
>> Yeah.
>> We know where all the targets are.
>> We we have excellent intelligence about
us.
>> Unbelievable.
>> We can kick our own ass as as as Rudy
Ray Moore used to say. We can kick our
own ass twice a day.
>> [laughter]
>> This got so bad that yesterday afternoon
Kier Starmer, the British prime
minister, had to come out and say,
"Look, you guys have to stop. You can't
have Greenland. You can't invade
Greenland. You can't attack Denmark.
We've got to come down on the side of
the Danes.
[laughter] They're a little slow to
this."
>> Yeah, a little bit. I think that the
Brits and others thought that they could
handle this directly with the Trump
administration in through back channels.
>> Yeah.
>> But then with this with this uh
interview by Steven Miller, you know,
back channels aren't working. [snorts]
>> I mean, there's so much to to I mean, so
okay, how serious do you think the
threat to Greenland is? before we go
back to Venezuela and take and answer
some more questions.
>> Yesterday I was asked about this in a
podcast and I made a face and just went,
"No." I said, "We're not going to take
Greenland." And then an hour later,
Steven Miller's on CNN saying, "We're
going to take Greenland." So I I think
this is this is like a a legit [snorts]
problem,
>> have to deal with.
>> So what's the solution for the from the
Danish point of view? They have to go to
NATO.
>> Yeah. and say, "We have a threat from
one of our from our lead member."
>> Yes.
>> And um
>> Who's who's the adult in the room?
>> Exactly.
>> Is it Emanuel Macron? Maybe. I'm not
even kidding. I mean,
>> I'm thinking that it is actually
>> because he's the one who's been uh
speaking intelligently about Venezuela.
>> And Donald Trump likes him. Mhm.
>> You know, I don't think Trump feels one
way or the other about Kier Starmer, but
I think Trump likes and respects
Mcronone.
>> And so maybe it's going to be up to
Mcronone to say, "Come on, you guys.
>> You have to stop."
>> I mean, the funny thing about Mcronone's
psychology is that, okay, so he honestly
he's in an abusive relationship. He's
obviously a child of abuse. And I'm not
saying this to be snotty, but it's true.
and having I know something about that
myself from my own upbringing. And one
thing that people like he and I uh are
able to do is we're able to keep things
calm when people are acting crazy. We're
able to not get riled up and and keep
our voice steady and and and talk like
the crazy alcoholic who's gonna hit you
down,
>> right? Um, Mron is is kind of dealing
with a not an alcohol. Well, kind of an
alcoholic, but he's dealing with a cra
This is [laughter]
>> Donald Trump is acting crazy.
>> Um, this doesn't make sense to me. I
don't understand. I I I you know, like I
said yesterday, Ted, I believed [snorts]
probably foolishly at this point that
MAGA was something that parts of MAGA,
elements of MAGA were were things that
people on the left and people on the
right could agree like anti-war
>> and and MAGA now we see is is not at all
anti-war. It's not
>> [music]
[music]